So it's for 11 people...
九 十 十一人份
It's been so long since I made a portion this large.
我好久没做这么多份餐点了
Kasane, do you usually cook?
重平常会做料理吗
Not really.
我不太会…
But Yuito sometimes does.
结人好像偶尔会做
The steel bowl should be right here.
我记得钢盆放在那里
How do you know?
妳怎么知道
The shelters for Sumeragis
皇家的避难所
are all the same.
几乎都一样
Let me whisk the eggs for you.
我帮忙打蛋吧
Really? I'll leave that to you.
可以吗 那就拜托妳啰
Mother.
妈妈
I never thought I could spend quiet time like this with you.
没想到能跟妳渡过这样的时光
SCARLET NEXUS
《绯红结系》
♫Felling of tiredness is losing yourself♫
倦怠感 losing yourself
♫How do you still create a relationship each other♫
尚未找到建立关系的方法吗
♫It’s my awkward friend’s fault♫
有个麻烦的朋友
♫Until death, wanting someone somewhere to embrace me♫
至死都在寻求某人的拥抱
♫While the devil is not here and between the chaos♫
在得以喘息的混沌虚无之间
♫Aiming between win and lose♫
以输赢之间为目标
♫Not to be running out of patience for now, I’m trying to be careful♫
注意别让信任走向尽头 务必小心
♫You’ll see I’m always on your side♫
You'll see I'm always on your side
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天仍拼命地联系着
♫You’re frigid and your roller coaster inside the brain♫
你脑中那冷感的轨道
♫The grungy days and the unprecedented catastrophy♫
摇滚的日子未曾有过的浩劫
♫Where is the glory buried?♫
光荣早已埋葬在某处
♫The lonely monster in a moment♫
这一瞬间寂寞孤独的野兽
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
与机关枪射出的子弹并列
♫To pierce with the theory♫
射穿所有世间道理
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天仍拼命地联系着
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
与机关枪射出的子弹并列
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天也仍在一起 清晰地联系着
♫You’re frigid and the theory in the brain♫
你那脑中冷感的正义
WAKANA'S RESOLVE
(若菜的决心)
Good morning, Yuito.
结人早安
Good morning.
早安
Are you feeling better now?
身体好多了吗
Much better now.
好多了
Shouldn't you take a break?
妈妈没有勉强自己吧
Time travel will exert a great amount of strain on the brain.
跳跃时空会给脑部带来较大的负担
I'm fine. Thank you for your concern.
我没事 谢谢你的关心
I heard a lot of things from Kasane.
重跟我说了许多事
After comparing the data sent by BABE,
跟贝比传送给我的数据对比
I've learned much about the situation.
让我理解了很多事
And about Karen...
还有 卡连的事也…
Powers can be very handy for things like this.
这种时候超脑力真的很方便
Well done, Yuito.
结人 做得很好喔
I actually like cooking.
我蛮喜欢做料理的
I can even do this.
还能这样
Impressive.
好厉害喔
I'll do the laundry.
我去洗衣服
Kasane...
重
It's all right.
没关系
-Mother, see you at dinner. -Sure.
-妈妈 吃饭见 -好
Mom, you need to take a break.
妈妈 妳坐着休息吧
Thanks, but I'll be fine.
谢谢 不过没关系
You're becoming more like your father.
你越来越像爸爸了
No way. Brother is more like him.
哪有 哥哥比我还像吧
People always say I don't look like my father.
大家经常说我长得不像爸爸
I don't mean the look. It's the aura.
不是指长相 而是感觉
How is Kaito lately?
界人最近好吗
Are you two getting along?
你们处得还好吗
He is fine. But I wouldn't say we are getting along.
他很好 但我跟他相处得不是很好
I see.
这样啊
Yuito, about your father...
结人 关于你爸爸的事
He saved me when Togetsu was hunting me down.
他救了被渡月追杀的我
He was a kind person.
是个温柔的人
As for Kaito, he's always wanted to be a politician
而界人则是为了改变这个国家
so he could change this country.
从小就志愿当个政治家
But he and I...
可是 我跟哥哥
It's all right.
没问题的
You two are both our children.
你们都是爸爸妈妈的孩子啊
Good morning.
早安
Thank you for the food.
我吃饱了
By the way,
话说回来
why is Wakana being sent back to her timeline?
若菜小姐为何 不会被强制送回原本时代呢
I am not particularly strong, but I am still a wielder of the Red Strings.
虽然我很弱小 但我仍是红色系线的脑力者
But we can't afford to get too careless, right?
不过也不能太悠闲 对吧
Yes.
对
If we don't eliminate the dimension entanglement inside the Kunad Gate,
如不尽快 消除岐之门内部的维度纠缠
the world will be destroyed very soon.
世界终将会毁灭
Dimension entanglement?
维度纠缠
It's the traces of time manipulation.
就是干涉时间的痕迹
The Kunad Gate is a dimensional portal formed during time travel.
岐之门 是跳跃时空时 暂时产生的次元之穴
And because it resonates with Yuito and Kasane's power,
因结人和重的力量起共鸣的缘故
it's been existing as a distorted form.
以歪斜的状态持续存在着
Yuito from the future said the same thing.
50年后的结人也这么说
A time travel via the distorted dimension
透过歪斜的空间做的时间跳跃
will create dimensional entanglement.
会产生维度纠缠
Undoing the dimensional entanglement will eliminate the Kunad Gate.
只要解开维度纠缠 就能关闭岐之门
What should we do?
我们该怎么做
Yuito, Kasane,
结人 重
you must both enter the Kunad Gate.
你们两人必须进入岐之门
Its inside is a conceptual space where only users of Red Strings exist subjectively.
里面是只有红色系线脑力者 主观存在的概念空间
Is it the space with a lot of weird images?
是那个有许多奇怪影像的空间吗
Yes.
没错
Togetsu called it the Chronos Terminal.
渡月称之为"克洛诺斯航站"
Chronos Terminal...
克洛诺斯航站…
A terminal of time flow.
时间流动的车站
Does it mean that's where timelines diverge?
也就是所谓的 分歧点吗
It's a space only Yuito and Kasane can understand.
只有结人和重能理解的空间啊
That must be why we didn't notice it even though we went to the future.
难怪我们曾到过未来 也曾发现
Even without traveling to that timeline,
即便不去该时代
a slight touch from the existence of the Red Strings users
红色系线脑力者的存在 稍微触碰一下
will create entanglement.
就会产生纠缠
As for which timelines created the entanglement,
实际上究竟哪些时代产生纠缠
you must search for them yourselves.
必须由你们自己去确认
In the end, we still have to rely on Yuito and Kasane.
结果还是只能拜托结人和重了
But after using the Red Strings...
可是 使用红色系线后又会…
Yuito, don't overdo it.
结人 你别太勉强喔
Yes.
好
Very well, let's go.
好 我们去吧
Mother, we'll be leaving now.
妈妈 走吧
What is it?
怎么了
Kasane, you grew up to become a great person.
重能成为一个好孩子
I'm so proud of you.
真是太好了
Well, I have no right to say that.
但我也没资格这么说
After all, I once abandoned you.
因为我曾抛下妳逃走
I'm so sorry.
真的很对不起
You don't have to apologize.
妈妈不用道歉
You almost lost your life back then.
当时妳差点被杀 而我…
I don't really remember what happened in Togetsu either.
也不记得在渡月的事了
Not to mention...
而且…
I had Naomi to keep my company after I came to Suoh.
到了苏芳之后 有直见姊姊陪我
I should really thank her for that.
那我得跟直见 好好道谢
To think you still consider me your mother...
妳仍愿意叫我一声 妈妈…
-Let's go. -Yes.
-我们走吧 -好
The dimensional entanglement is like red threads that are entangled.
维度纠缠 就像是被缠在一起的红丝线
You know how to undo the knots.
你们应该知道如何解开纠缠
Come back immediately if it gets too risky.
感觉有危险的话 就立刻回来
Yes.
好
As for my mother...
各位 我母亲就…
Don't worry, you can count on us.
放心 不用担心
We will keep Wakana safe.
我们会保护若菜小姐
-Thank you. -You have my thanks.
-谢谢你们 -谢谢
Now, are you ready?
好了 两位准备好了吗
-Kasane, are you ready? -Yes.
-重 可以吗 -可以
You must stay focused.
两人集中精神
Imagine the view of Chronos Terminal.
想象克洛诺斯航站的景象
Chronos Terminal...
克洛诺斯航站
I will undo the dimensional entanglement.
我定会解开维度纠缠
-I think we made it. -Yeah.
-好像到了 -是啊
Yuito, Kasane, over here.
结人 重 这里
Mother?
妈妈
Can you see it?
看到了吗
There are entanglement spots up ahead.
前方 有许多纠缠
Thank you, Mother.
谢谢妈妈
Leave the rest to us.
之后就交给我们吧
Yes. Be careful.
好 小心喔
Is this it?
就是这个吗
We just need to undo this entanglement from different timelines.
只要到各个时代解开纠缠就行了吧
Let's start with this.
首先是这里
It's the old OSF hospital from the other day.
是那天的旧怪伐军医院
Is this the inside of dimensional entanglement?
这里就是维度纠缠里吗
-Let's use the Red Strings. -Yes. That should undo this thing.
-使用红色系线 -对 应该就能解开
It's not separating.
看来不能分开解
We need to do it together.
我们得一起解
Concentrate and continue.
集中精神 继续
Yes.
好
Take care of that line.
这条拜托你
Let's keep it going.
继续
We can do this.
看来应该可行
Not bad, Kasane. You're the older sister I can count on.
不愧是重 果然是姊姊
What do you mean?
什么意思啊
But you were born first.
因为 重先出生的嘛
We're of the same age.
但我们岁数相同
Kyoka said it was because of your cryosleep.
镜花说因为做过冷冻睡眠
But I must thank you.
不过 我真的很感谢妳
For what?
谢什么
You saved me that day.
谢谢妳 那天救了我
I haven't thanked you yet.
我还没好好跟妳道谢呢
Why are you bringing this up now?
怎么突然想道谢
That was the day I started using my power.
我从那时 开始能使用力量
Maybe I got a tiny portion of power from you too.
搞不好 是妳分了一些力量给我
Brain power cannot be shared.
超脑力是无法分给别人的
I know.
我知道
However...
不过…
I'm only alive now because we met that day.
因为有那天的相遇 我才能活到现在
That's when I decided to join OSF.
也有了成为怪伐军的目标
Kasane, thank you.
所以 重 谢谢妳
Thank you for saving me.
谢谢妳救了我
This is when I say
这种时候应该说
you're welcome. Am I right?
不客气 对吧
Now, this is the last thread.
好了 最后一条
-Our next target... -Suoh, 50 years from now.
-再来是 -50年后的苏芳京
It's the entanglement created when I met the future you.
遇见未来的你 而产生的纠缠
This is Suoh 50 years into the future?
这里是50年后的苏芳
Come, I know where it is.
走吧 我知道在哪
Yuito.
结人
What if you could rewrite history?
你曾想过如果能改变历史就好了吗
Do you mean by time travel?
是指跳跃时空到过去吗
Wouldn't that create a new dimensional entanglement?
这样 不会产生心的纠缠吗
I mean after the Kunad Gate is destroyed.
我说的是岐之门消失后的事
What if you could travel to any timeline you wanted?
如果能来去自如各个时代的情况
I thought about it.
我想过
I wish I had done it long ago.
后悔当时如果这么做就好了
Yuito.
结人
Since I'm dying anyway,
既然都要死…
What should I do?
我…该怎么做才好呢…
I couldn't answer Nagi's question.
我当时无法回答那岐
Will you use the Red Strings to go back in time?
那么 你想使用红色系线 回到过去吗
No.
不想
Even if I change the past,
就算改变了过去
the future is still full of uncertainties.
未来仍是未知数
If Nagi hadn't become my friend,
而且 那岐如果没跟我成为朋友
maybe he wouldn't have gotten caught up in all of this.
或许就不会被牵扯进来
If I had never met Nagi,
如果我没跟那岐相遇
we wouldn't pursue the same dream.
就不会一起追逐憧憬的梦想
To change the past over that
为了这样而改变过去
is just not right.
我不认为是正确的
Nagi deserves to have his own future.
那岐有属于他自己的未来
Just like the entanglement, nothing is absolute.
就如同纠缠一般 不能说是正确
Changing another person's life based on my opinion
以自己的想法而改变他人的人生
is just not right.
我认为这是不对的
I'm sorry for asking that strange question.
抱歉 我问了奇怪的问题
But I'm surprised.
不过我好惊讶
I was thinking about the same thing.
因为我也是这么想的
In the past, I might have given a different answer.
或许以前的我 会给出不同的答案
I've had a different view of the world after meeting everyone.
跟大家相处后 让我看到不同的世界观
I understand. It was the same for me.
我懂 因为我也是
We share quite a lot in common, actually.
其实 我们还挺合的嘛
Don't get ahead of yourself.
这么想或许还太早了
Sorry...
抱歉…
This is it.
果然是这里
We'll start from the right side.
从右边开始解吧
Yes.
好
Kasane, are you all right?
重 没事吧
Sorry. I'm fine.
抱歉 我没事
Very well. Now, the left side.
好 剩下左边了
Yes.
是啊
Kasane, you can do it. Just a little more!
重 加油 快好了
I'll support that thread.
这一束我来支撑
That's the last one.
只剩下那条
Kasane!
重
I'm fine.
我没事
Just one entanglement left.
剩下最后一个纠缠
Yes.
是啊
Is that...
那是…
The crest of Sumeragi!
皇家纹
That's what I saw when I first came in here!
那是我们第一次来这里时 看到的影像
Just as Mother said,
跟妈妈说的一样
Another entanglement was created
那是触碰到脑力者的我们
when we came into contact with another power user.
就产生了维度纠缠
It's Karen!
卡连
What's going on?
发生什么事了
I don't know.
不知道
But this is going to get worse.
不过 再这样下去会很严重
-Let's do this. -Yes.
-开始吧 -好
Not now! It's the overexertion of brain power...
这种时候 脑力使用过度吗…
No, we need to be faster.
不好 我们动作快
Did we make it?
成功了吗…
Yuito, Kasane.
结人 重
Are we back?
我们回来了吗
You've both safe. Thank goodness.
你们都没事吧 太好了
Yeah, we somehow made it.
是啊 勉强没事
Is the Kunad Gate...
这样岐之门就…
Why is it still here?
为何还没消失
You did well.
辛苦了
You both did great.
你们真的很努力
It's all right now.
已经没事了
But...
可是…
Mother, we undo the entanglements.
妈妈 我们解开了纠缠
But why...
但为什么…
Leave the rest to me.
之后就交给我吧
Mother...
妈妈
You've made a lot of friends.
你们交到了许多好朋友
This friendship is more precious than any Red String.
这之间的羁绊 比任何一条红丝线还要有价值
Cherish it.
要好好珍惜喔
Thank you. You've become so strong.
谢谢你们 成长得这么好
Mom, are you going back now?
妈妈 妳要回到过去吗
If you do, Togetsu...
回去的话 渡月会…
It must be done.
这是必须的
Sorry, but staying here with you
对不起 继续跟你们在一起
just doesn't seem right to me.
我会很不舒服的
Wait! I still have so much to tell you!
等等 我还有很多话要跟妳说
Mother...
妈妈
Yuito, Kasane...
结人 重
May you have a happy life in the future.
祝你们 活在幸福的未来
-Mother! -Mom!
-妈妈
Another entanglement was created when you traveled through time.
妈妈跳跃时空时产生了纠缠
How did it happen?
怎么会这样
As long as I stay, the Kunad Gate will continue to exist.
继续留在这 岐之门就不会消失
That was what she said.
她是这么说的
She left a message.
她有留下留言
Yuito, Kasane.
结人 重
I'm sorry this is how I bid you farewell.
抱歉 以这个方式跟你们告别
I should have told you in person.
其实我应该自己跟你们说
But I don't think I'll be calm enough to explain everything to you.
但我没自信能在你们面前 冷静地说明一切
I must return to my own timeline.
我要回去自己的时空
No, I'll already be there.
不 应该是已经回去了
I've made up my mind when I received the data from BABE.
当我接收贝比的数据时 就这么决定了
I must fulfill my duty
我必须在自己的时空
in my own timeline.
完成自己的人生责任
I could receive the data from Togetsu
我之所以能接受 渡月传送出来的数据
because they retrieved my brain.
就是因为脑部被渡月收回
A connection was formed between BABE and me.
与贝比产生连结
This outcome will surely make you sad.
这个结果必定会让你们感到难过
But I feel so happy.
不过 我很开心喔
I now know my two beloved children
能看到我重要的两个孩子
have grown up to become so strong and amazing.
都长大成人的模样
You can have my brain,
就算把脑给你们
but you cannot take away my memory of the future.
但未来的记忆也绝不交给你们
I'm sure the two of you can overcome anything.
相信你们之后不论遇到什么 都不会有问题
I'm grateful that you've come into this world.
谢谢你们的出生
Thank you for being alive
以及 好好活下来
and bringing my happiness.
并给了我幸福
Kaito.
界人
Yuito.
结人
Kasane.
重
Jo.
条…
WARNING, EXECUTING
(危险 执行中)
DELETION COMPLETE
(消除完成)
I hope the happiness you will have
我祈愿将造访两人的幸福
is so much more than what I received.
是我所得到的 好几倍
Yuito, Kasane.
结人 重
I love you.
我爱你们
PLAYBACK ENDED
(播放结束)
♫I'm troubled by my own yearning♫
被追求的憧憬所困
♫Unveil the blocked sun ray♫
揭开被阻挡的摇曳阳炎
♫There's a stranger in me♫
There's a stranger in me
♫That I've never seen♫
从未见过
♫I can not soar in the sky without fear♫
自己能不再恐惧翱翔高空
♫I'm spreading my wings♫
I'm spreading my wings
♫Dancing gracefully like a bird♫
华丽舞步的鸟儿
♫And gazing towards the scarlet sky♫
仰望染红的天空
♫I chased after the gust♫
追过了强风
♫The scenery spreads into the ever-changing world♫
景色蔓延在千变万化的世界里
♫Inside the intertwined brilliance♫
在交错的光芒中
♫I'm still searching for tomorrow's direction♫
持续寻找明天的行径方向
♫Tomorrow's in your hands♫
Tomorrow's in your hands
♫Don't tell me now you're afraid♫
Don't tell me now you're afraid
♫There's no time to waste♫
There's no time to waste
♫Go forward♫
前进
♫Have no fear for anything♫
不再畏惧何物
♫Now, let's go♫
走吧
♫Into a brand new day♫
Into a brand new day
THE TWO BROTHERS
(兄与弟)